<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sophie Bosio</title>
    <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sophie Bosio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 22:42:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Emacs LSP-Mode For Clojure</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/lsp-mode-for-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 22:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/lsp-mode-for-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; on the backend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ardoq.com/&#34;&gt;where I work&lt;/a&gt;. I think it&amp;rsquo;s really fun, especially in combination with Emacs, since Emacs is built with Emacs Lisp and Clojure is a Lisp dialect. So many of Emacs&amp;rsquo; default keybindings started clicking for me once I started working with a language in the same tradition, editing structurally and by semantic units rather than line-by-line or character-by-character. I&amp;rsquo;m not alone in loving both and there&amp;rsquo;s clearly a lot of overlap between the two communities, which is evident from the number of Clojure packages for Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First Emacs Config</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/first-emacs-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 23:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/first-emacs-config/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful piece of software. It&amp;rsquo;s easily my favourite program of all
time. It can also be a little overwhelming to configure for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the many things that make Emacs great, though, is its dedicated and
helpful user base. I hope to add a small contribution to that community with
this post, going over what I would have told my past self as I was just starting
out using Emacs and trying to write my first Emacs configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prettifying Emacs Org Mode</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/prettifying-emacs-org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 22:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/prettifying-emacs-org-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the power of Emacs is that you&amp;rsquo;re able to program your own
working environment. Other editors may be just as, or possibly more, efficient
to use, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across any that give you control over as many aspects
of your editor as Emacs does. Customising and tweaking your configuration may be an
endless endeavour, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a highly rewarding one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that being said, I was inspired to tweak the look of my Org Mode setup,
especially after reading the blog post
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zzamboni.org/post/beautifying-org-mode-in-emacs/&#34;&gt;Beautifying
Org Mode in Emacs&lt;/a&gt;. Below you can find screenshots and code. I
hope there&amp;rsquo;s something in here that you might want to steal for your own config!
In case I change these settings later, my most recently updated config is always
available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SophieBosio/.emacs.d&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Generation with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 12:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This website is built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an exporting engine that lets me
write my posts in &lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/&#34;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt; and then put it online easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Org mode is a really clever and powerful plain text format that works great for note
taking, text editing, and TODO lists/agendas. Moreover, there are a lot of
convenient features for us Emacs users when using &lt;code&gt;ox-hugo&lt;/code&gt; to write our blogs
(besides staying in the comfort of a well-known format and editing flow).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
