<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on PaperMod</title>
    <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on PaperMod</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:24:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Small Interpreter in Haskell</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/boa-interpreter-haskell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/boa-interpreter-haskell/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite assignments in my advanced functional programming course, was implementing a parser and interpreter for a subset of Python, called Boa, in Haskell.
We&amp;rsquo;d just started getting a grasp of what monads are and how they work, and this project is what really solidified it for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we approached it and some of my reflections when looking back at it.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on the interpreter, because we implemented the monad for the interpreter by hand, and I feel it&amp;rsquo;s easier to see how monads work when seeing the implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautifying Emacs Org Mode</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/beautifying-emacs-org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 22:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/beautifying-emacs-org-mode/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, the power of Emacs is that you&amp;rsquo;re able to program your own working environment. Other editors may be just as, or possibly more, efficient to use, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across any that give you control over as many aspects of your editor as Emacs does. Customising and tweaking your configuration may be an endless endeavour, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a highly rewarding one.
All that being said, I was inspired to tweak the look of my Org Mode setup, especially after reading this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Generation with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 12:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophiebosio.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid>
      <description>This website is built with Hugo and ox-hugo, an exporting engine that lets me write my posts in Org mode and then put it online easily.
Org mode is a really clever and powerful plain text format that works great for note taking, text editing, and TODO lists/agendas. Moreover, there are a lot of convenient features for us Emacs users when using ox-hugo to write our blogs (besides staying in the comfort of a well-known format and editing flow).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
